A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, New York Republican State Fund Raising Reports, Series 38 FA376
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nelson A. Rockefeller gubernatorial records, New York Republican State Fund Raising Reports, Series 38
1967-1973
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
New York (State). Governor (1959-1973: Rockefeller)
Hellmuth, James G.
FA376
1.31 Cubic Feet 1 standard record storage box.
Biographical/Historical note
Nelson A. Rockefeller served as governor of New York from January 1, 1959, to December 18, 1973. He was the first person elected to four consecutive four-year terms as a state governor.
File Plan note
Former Classification: III 15 38
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents note
This series consists of copies of financial reports of New York Republican fund raising committees, dated 1967 to 1973, filed with the New York Secretary of State in accordance with New York State election laws at the time. There are 10 reports from the New York Republican State Dinner Committee and 19 reports from the Governor's Club. These are file copies of reports sent to the Secretary of State by James G. Hellmuth, who served as treasurer for both organizations. All but three reports have cover letters from Hellmuth. Attached to the cover letter of most of the reports are certified mail receipts and return receipts from mailing the original reports.
The reports consist of Schedule A--receipts--and Schedule B--disbursements. Schedule A is an itemized list of contributions which include the name and address of each contributor and the date and amount of the contribution. Contributions are listed in the order in which they were received, thus finding a particular name is time consuming. Schedule B is a short list of expenses and contributions. With three exceptions all the contributions from both organizations were to the New York Republican State Committee. However, the Dinner Committee made contributions to the New York Republican County Committee in 1968, to the United Service Organization in 1969, and to the Friends of the Rockefeller Team in 1971. The Governor's Club maintained a running balance from year to year, while the Dinner Committee contributed the entire balance, after expenses, at the end of each year.
Other than a covering letter these reports contain no correspondence, charter, or promotional literature or any other evidence of the nature of these organizations or who ran them. Since the reason for each expense is summarized in one or two words, Schedule B offers scant clues about the types of premiums offered in return for a contribution.
The size of the individual contributions was evidently in response to appeals for certain amounts. The contributions listed in the 1968 report for the Governor's Club, for example, are either for $100 or $500, mostly the latter. Members of the Rockefeller family are found among the contributors in each of these reports. Rockefellers contributing to the Governor's Club include NAR's brothers--John D. 3rd, Laurance S., Winthrop, and David Rockefeller--and his sons Rodman and Steven. Their contributions are in the $100 to $500 range like all the others. An exception is in 1973 when David and Laurance each contributed $5,000 in additional to their usual $500 contribution. Regular Rockefeller contributors to the Dinner Committee include NAR, John 3rd, Laurance, David and Martha Baird Rockefeller, NAR's stepmother. NAR's sister, Abby Rockefeller Mauze, contributed in 1970 and 1971. The size of these contributions is at the high end of the scale; $1,500 each in 1967 and 1968, $3,000 each in the years following. An exception is 1970, the year of NAR's costliest gubernatorial campaign, when four family members made contributions of $6,000 each. The most common amount from other contributors to the Dinner Committee was $150. NAR's former wife, Mary C. Rockefeller, made a $500 contribution in 1967.
The volume numbers were added when the material was processed in 1999.
Other Finding Aids note
Detailed finding aids for each series of this collection are available:
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Appointments Office (FA353)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Assembly and Senate Memos (FA354)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Joseph H. Boyd (FA355)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, James Cannon (FA356)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Affirmative Action (N. Lee Cook) (FA357)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Counsel's Office (FA358)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York State Committee to Reelect the President (FA359)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Jerry A. Danzig (FA360)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Executive Chamber (FA361)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, 55th Street (FA362)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Issue Books (FA363)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Arthur Massolo (FA364)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Hugh Morrow (FA242)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York Office (FA365)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Civil Service Resolutions (Charles H. Palmer) (FA366)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Political Files (FA367)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Press Office (FA368)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Public Relations (FA369)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Departmental Reports (FA370)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, William J. Ronan (FA371)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Speeches (FA372)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Diane Van Wie (FA373)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Ann C. Whitman, Gubernatorial (FA374)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Gene Wyckoff (FA375)
Federal government -- United States; Government policy; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1958; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1962; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1966; Presidential candidates -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Public policy; Public relations; Affirmative action programs -- New York (State); Arms control; Arms control -- United States; Civil defense; Civil defense -- United States; Civil service; Civil service -- New York (State); Economics; United States; State governments -- United States; Vice-Presidents -- United States; International relations -- United States; Latin America; Legislation -- New York (State); New York (N.Y.); Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1970; Human rights; International economic relations; International relations; New York (State); Political campaigns -- United States; Political science; Presidential campaigns -- United States
- Governor's Club - Filed October 28, 1967 for the period December 31, 1966 - October 28, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Governor's Club - Filed November 27, 1967 for the period October 28 - November 27, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Governor's Club - Filed January 2, 1968 for the period November 22 - December 29, 1967, 1967-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Governor's Club - Filed October 28, 1968 for the period December 29, 1967 - October 28, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Governor's Club - Filed November 25, 1968 for the period October 29 - November 25, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Governor's Club - Filed January 2, 1969 for the period November 26 - December 31, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Governor's Club - Filed October 24, 1969 for the period January 1 - October 24, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Governor's Club - Filed November 24, 1969 for the period October 27 - November 24, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Governor's Club - Filed January 2, 1970 for the period November 25 - December 31, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Governor's Club - Filed October 23, 1970 for the period January 1 - October 23, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Governor's Club - Filed November 23, 1970 for the period October 26 - November 23, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Governor's Club - Filed January 2, 1971 for the period November 24 - December 31, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Governor's Club - Filed December 31, 1971 for the period January 1 - December 31, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Governor's Club - Filed October 27, 1972 for the period January 10 - October 27, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Governor's Club - Filed November 27, 1972 for the period October 27 - November 27, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Governor's Club - Filed January 2, 1973 for the period November 28, 1972 - January 2, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Governor's Club - Filed October 25, 1973 for the period January 3 - October 25, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Governor's Club - Filed November 21, 1973 for the period October 26 - November 21, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Governor's Club - Filed December 31, 1973 for the period November 22 - December 31, 1973. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- New York Republican State Dinner Committee - Filed October 20, 1967, final report for 1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- New York Republican State Dinner Committee - Filed October 28, 1968 for the period March 7 - October 28, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- New York Republican State Dinner Committee - Filed November 25, 1968, final report for 1968 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- New York Republican State Dinner Committee - Filed October 24, 1969 for the period March 14 - October 24, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- New York Republican State Dinner Committee - Filed November 24, 1969 for the period October 27 - November 24, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- New York Republican State Dinner Committee - Filed December 24, 1969, final report for 1969 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- New York Republican State Dinner Committee - Filed October 16, 1970, final report for 1970, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- New York Republican State Dinner Committee - Filed September 20, 1971, final report for 1971 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- New York Republican State Dinner Committee - Filed October 19, 1972, final report for 1972 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- New York Republican State Dinner Committee - Filed October 25, 1973, final report for 1973 (Box 1, Folder 29)